Finding Aid for the Edouard Roditi Papers LSC.0644
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Manuscripts by Édouard Roditi and others.
  - CRYSTAL NIGHT..., THE LAST ESCAPE, I CLANDESTINI DEL MARC, DE GAULLE [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: EUROPEAN JUDAISM. DE GAULLE: LES GAULLISTES ET ISRAEL by Samy Cohen.
    Thalmann, Rita and Feinermann, Emmanuel. Crystal night: 9-10 November 1983.
    Aliav, Ruth and Mann, Peggy. The last escape.
    Sereni, Ada. I clandestini del Marc.
  - DARK GATE by David Vogel [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. Full title: THE DARK GATE. ER's note: sent to MODERN POETRY IN TRANSLATION.
  - DIARIO APROCRIFO DE OCTAVIO DE ROMEU by Juan Perucho [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
    Perucho, Juan. Dietario aprocrifo de Octavio de Romeu.
  - DRESS OF FIRE by Dahlia Ravikovitch [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
    MODERN POETRY IN TRANSLATION.
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: MODERN POETRY IN TRANSLATION. Full title: A DRESS OF FIRE.
  - DU SOLLST NICHT TOETEN by Hans Werner Richter [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscripts. ER's note: LETTRES ETRANGERES, SUPPLEMENT, PREUVES.
  - DUTCH DRAWINGS AND PRINTS by J.G. Van Gelder [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. With ER's note: Published in ART NEWS AND REVIEW (?)
  - EINES FENSTERS SCHATTEN ... Wolfgang Schlueter [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1985. (Box 54)
    Schlueter, Wolfgang. Enes Fensters schatten, oder: Mercurius' Hochzeit met der Philosophie.
  - ELOGES AND OTHER POEMS by St. John Perse [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: POETRY.
  - ERIK SATIE by Ornelle Volta [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1979. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: WORLD LITERATURE TODAY, 1979.
  - GREAT OFFENSIVE by Max Werner [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. Full title: THE GREAT OFFENSIVE. TER's note: TOMORROW MAGAZINE.
  - HISTORIA DE LAS LITERATURAS DE VANGUARDIA by Guillermo de Torre; PICABIA by Sanouillet [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
    Sanouillet, Michel. Picabia, l'oeil du temps.
  - INTRODUCTION ... REPERTOIRE DE LA CORRESPONDANCE DE MARCEL PROUST by Pierre Raphael [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: BOOKS ABROAD, 1946 ?
  - ISAAC ROSENBERG. COMPLETE WORKS. [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
  - JOSEL VON ROSHEIM by Selma Stern [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: published? EVIDENCES, Paris.
  - LA BRUIT DES AUTRES by Jacques Sabbath [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1974. (Box 54)
  - LA CLAIRIERE DANS LA PINEDE, et LE COMPLEXE DE MIDAS by Youri Tarnopolski [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1988. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: 1988, PLEIN CHANT.
  - LA CORBEILLE D'IGNAMES by Penda, LES AVENTURES DE MONI-MAMBOU by Guy Menga [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1972. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: BOOKS ABROAD, 1972.
  - LA GRANDE SALLE by Jacoba Van Velde [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: PREUVES, Paris, LETTRES ETRANGERES SUPPLEMENT.
  - LA SALLE DE BAIN by Jean-Philippe Toussaint [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
  - LA VERITE ET LES MYTHES: ENTRETIENS ET ESSAIS by Gaetan Picon [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
  - LA VIDE PERRA DE JUANITA NARBONI by Angel Vasquez [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1977. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. ER'S note: WORLD LITERATURE TODAY, 1977.
  - L'APPRENTISSAGE INUTILE by David Scheinert [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1986. (Box 54)
    Typecript with holograph corrections. ER's note: WORLD LITERATURE TODAY, 1986.
  - L'ART JUIF: ORIENT ET OCCIDENT by Gabrielle Sed-Rajna [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1976. (Box 54)
  - LE FRONT DE L'ART, 1939-1940 by Rose Vailland [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: ARTS.
  - LE JAPON ET SON EMPIRE, et CHANGHAI ET LA DESTIN DE LA CHINE by Andre Viollis [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. Signed by ER on page 4.
  - LE LADINO (JUDEO-ESPAGNOL CALQUE). DEUTERONOME ... by Haim Vidal Sephiha [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
  - LE ROI ET LA REINE by Ramon Sender [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 54)
    Sender, Ramon. Le roi et la reine.
  - LEON BLUM: FROM POET TO PREMIER by Richard L. Stokes [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1934. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: THE SPECTATOR, London, 1934.
  - LES ABRIS MENSONGERS by Carlo Suares [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: EUROPEAN JUDAISM.
  - LES AMITIES LOINTAINES by David Scheinert, DAVID SCHEINERT by Lazlo Ferenczi [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
  - LES INSECTES SOCIAUX by O.W. Richards [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. With clipping of the review, LECTURES ETRANGERES, PREUVES.
  - L'ETRE ET LE NEANT by J.P. Sartre [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. With extra copy of page 3.
  - L'HORLOGE ELEMENTAIRE by David Scheinert {book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. With ER's note: WORLD LITERATURE TODAY.
  - LIMBO by Bernard Wolfe [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
  - L'INCONNU by Erico Verissimo [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. With note: LECTURES ETRANGERES #3 March 1956.
  - MAIDEN VOYAGE by Denton Welch [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
  - MANNER MUSIC by Charles Reznikoff [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. Full title: THE MANNER MUSIC.
  - MARCEL PROUST by Leon Pierre-Quint [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1977. (Box 54)
  - MON FRERE FEMININ by Marina Zvetaieva [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1979. (Box 54)
  - MOSCOW DATELINE, 1941-1943, THE UNKNOWN ARMY, TWELVE MONTHS THAT CHANGED THE WORLD [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: TOMORROW.
    Cassidy, Henry C. Moscow dateline, 1941-1943.
    Lesueur, Larry. Twelve months that changed the world.
    Basseches, Mikolaus. The unknown army.
  - MOUCHE-TOI by Francoise Xenakis [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1987. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. With ER's note: L'INGENU, Paris, 1987.
  - NEUE MALTEREI IN OESTERREICH by Gerhard Schmidt [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
    Holograph title: Austrian art. Pages numbered 1,2,4.
  - PAR LES CHEMINS D'EMIGRATION by Malek Ouary [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: JANA, Ceylon.
  - PAUL GOODMAN ET LA RECONQUETE DU PRESENT by Bernard Vincent [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1977. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: WORLD LITERATURE TODAY ?, 1977.
  - PICABIA by Michel Senouillet [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
  - POEMES POUR LE JEU DU SILENCE by Jerome Rotherberg [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1970. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: L'ARCHE, Paris, 1970.
  - POEMS by Stephen Spender [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1931?. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. ER'S NOTES: THE SPECTATOR, 1931?
  - POEMS by Wilfred Owen ... notes by Edmund Blunden [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 54)
    Owen, Wilfred. Poems, with a memoir and notes by Edmund Blunden.
    Rosenberg, Isaac
  - POUR UN BON USAGE DU MONDE by Bernard Vincent [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1980. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. With ER's note: EUROPEAN JUDAISM, London, 1980.
    Vincent, Bernard. Pour un bon usage du monde. Un reponse conviviale a la crise de l'ecole ...
  - POUR UN BON USAGE DU MONDE by Bernard Vincent [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 54)
  - RITES: A GUATEMALAN BOYHOOD by Victor Perera [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
  - SAKRILEG by Jan Tauschinski [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
  - Salad and a dressing [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 54)
    Review of 100 MODERN POEMS, edited by Selden Rodman.
  - SEASON IN HELL by Arthur Rimbaud [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
    POETRY. CHICAGO.
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: POETRY: A MAGAZINE OF VERSE. Full title: A SEASON IN HELL.
  - SHEM TOV: HIS WORLD AND HIS WORDS by Sanford Shepard [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 54)
  - SONNETS by Shakespeare, translated by Pierre Jean Jouve [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: PREUVES, Paris.
    Shakespeare. Sonnets.
    Jouve, Pierre Jean, trans.
  - STAEDTE UND MENSCHEN. BEITRAEGE by Hilde Spiel [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: Sent to BOOKS ABROAD but not published.
  - TABLEAU DE LA LITTERATURE FRANCAISE ..., INTRODUCTION A LA POESIE FRANCAISE by Roditi, Edouard., 1940. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: BOOKS ABROAD, 1940.
  - THOMAS PAINE, OU LA RELIGION DE LA LIBERTE by Robert Vincent [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.p. (Box 54)
  - TIGERS ON THE TENTH DAY by Zakaria Tamer [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1985. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: sent to WORLD LITERATURE TODAY, 1985.
  - UN CRI SANS VOIX by Henri Raczymow [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1987. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: HOLOCAUST & GENOCIDE STUDIES, Oxford, 1987.
  - UNKNOWN MURDERER by Theodor Reik [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 54)
    Untitled manuscript. Full title: THE UNKNOWN MURDERER.
  - VISITAS by Gilbert Trolliet [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1973. (Box 54)
  - Bomb by Chevalier, Haakon., n.d. (Box 55)
    Roditi, Edouard, ed.
    Title: The bomb. ER's note: "Haakon Chevalier's last unfinished and unpublished book, edited by Edouard Roditi".
  - Abecederien de la lubricite by Laughlin, James. (Box 55)
  - Olympic machinations by Riordan, Terence, pseud., 1964. (Box 55)
    ER's note: NEW LEADER, [6/22/64]. Terence Riordan is one of Roditi's pseudonyms.
  - Allegory and alienation [THE OTHER SIDE by Alfred Kubin - book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1968. (Box 55)
    ER's note: ARTS IN SOCIETY, Summer 1968.
  - ALORS, LES OISEAUX SONT PARTIS by Yachar Kemal [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 55)
  - American Romantic fiction - introduction [German] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 55)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: Introduction to unpublished German anthology of nineteenth century American writers. Berlin publisher wnet out of business as result of the blockade.
  - ART OF THE RENAISSANCE IN NORTHERN EUROPE by Otto Benesch [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 55)
    Untitled manuscript. Full title: THE ART OF THE RENAISSANCE IN NORTHERN EUROPE.
  - AXIS GRAND STRATEGY edited by Ladislas Farago [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 55)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: TOMORROW. Full title: THE AXIS GRAND STRATEGY.
  - Benkemoun by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 55)
  - CANDLES AND ROSES by Roman Basu [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 55)
  - Cavritico: the Salonica-Judeo Spanish Had Gadya by Roditi, Edouard., 1979. (Box 55)
    ER's note: Translated into Portugeuse in OCIDENTE, revised for JUDAISM, 1979.
  - Concentration camp literature by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 55)
    Untitled manuscript. Specific discussion of FERIEN AM WALDSEE by Carl Laszlo and TANGUY by Miguel de Castillo.
  - DAS GOLDENE ZEITALTER by Kurt Erich Meurer [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1949. (Box 55)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: BOOKS ABROAD?, 1949.
  - Delights of Turkey: Man culture and education by Roditi, Edouard., [1 of 5 folders] (Box 55)
    Page 16 is a typescript(carbon). Full title: A manof culture and education.
  - Delights of Turkey: Ghost with an American passport by Roditi, Edouard., n.d.; [2 of 5 folders] (Box 55)
    Full title: The ghost with an American passport.
  - Delights of Turkey: Night of love by Roditi, Edouard., n.d.; [3 of 5 folders] (Box 55)
    Full title: A night of love.
  - Delights of Turkey: Three faiths, one god by Roditi, Edouard., n.d.; [4 of 5 folders] (Box 55)
  - Delights of Turkey: Angel of death by Roditi, Edouard., n.d.; [5 of 5 folders] (Box 55)
  - DER WINTER IST EIN ANDERES LAND by Gabriel Gafita [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1984. (Box 55)
  - Earthly paradise by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 55)
  - Editions CLE by Roditi, Edouard., 1972. (Box 55)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: CONTINENT 2000 Jan. or Feb. 1972. With copies in English and French. French translations are signed Nissim Bernard, one of ER's pseudonyms.
  - Elegy on fashions in death by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 55)
  - Entretien avec Haim Potok by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 55)
    ER's note: L'ARCHE.
    Potok, Haim
    Potok, Chaim
  - Entretien avec l'auteur de LA SOLUTION FINALE by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 55)
  - FASCISM by Alfred Werner [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 55)
    Untitled manuscrpt. ER's note: ARTISTS.
  - GEOGRAPHIE DE MARCEL PROUST by Andre Ferre [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1940?. (Box 55)
    Untitled manuscript. ER'S note: BOOKS ABROAD, 1940?
    Ferre, Andre. Geographie de Marcel Proust.
  - Grandees or pretenders by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 55)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: Original text of article published in COMMENTARY.
  - Holocaust [book reviews] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 55)
    Untitled manuscripts. ER's note: COMMENTARY. Reviews of KOMMANDANT IN AUSCHWITZ (Hoess), LA NUIT (Wiesel), L'AFFAIRE AUDIN (Vidal-Nacquet), LA QUESTION ALGERIENNE (Dresch, et al.).
  - Hommage a Sandro Penna by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 55)
    ER's note: ARCADIE, Paris. Signed Edouard Roditi, published under his pseudonym Nissim Bernard.
  - Hopeful poem by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 55)
    Original title "The sexual problem" has been crossed out. The manuscript itself is untitled. ER's note: SPARROW 64, Black Sparrow Press, 1978.
  - JEWS OF RHODES ... by Marc D. Angel [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 55)
    Untitled manuscript. Full title: THE JEWS OF RHODES.
    Angel, Marc D. The Jews of Rhodes: the history of a sephardic community.
  - Journal of an apprentice cabbalist: Introduction to a vita nuova by Roditi, Edouard., 1988. (Box 55)
    ER's note: written originally in 1931, revised 1988.
  - LA VICE-PRESIDENT by John Marquant [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1955. (Box 55)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: PREUVES LECTURES ETRANGERES SUPPLEMENT.
  - L'ABIME ET AUTRES RECITS by Sadeq Hedayat [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1987. (Box 55)
  - LE VISIONNAIRE by Julien Green [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 55)
  - LES BOSTONIENNES by Henry James, translated by Jeanne Colin-Lemercier [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 55)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: PREUVES. With holograph notes and clipping of the review.
  - LES DEMONS by Fedor Dostoievsky, translated by Boris de Schloezer & Sylvie Luneau [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 55)
  - LES EUROPEENS by Henry James, translated by Denis Van Moppes [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1955. (Box 55)
  - LES JUIFS A LA FIN DU MOYEN AGE DANS L'EUROPE MEDITERRANEENNE by Maurice Kriegel [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1979. (Box 55)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: PRESENT TENSE, New York, 1979.
  - LES NOUVELLES NOURRITURES by Andre Gide [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1934?. (Box 55)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: THE SPECTATOR, 1934?
  - LES OMBRES VERTES DU PRINTEMPS by Cecily Mackworth [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 55)
    Untitled manuscript. ER'S note: PREUVES.
  - Letter from Portugal by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 55)
    ER's note: NEW YORK TIMES BOOK REVIEW.
  - L'INSTINCT DU BONHEUR by Andre Maurois [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 55)
  - Maurice Sachs by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 55)
  - Message from Erewhones by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 55)
    ER's note: First draft.
  - MESSENGERS FROM THE DEAD: LITERATURE OF THE HOLOCAUST by Irving Halperin [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1971. (Box 55)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: EUROPEAN JUDAISM, 1971.
  - MOSAIQUES DE NOTRE MEMOIRE: LES JUDEO-ESPAGNOLS DU MAROC [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1983. (Box 55)
  - NON LIEU: BENJAMIN FONDANE [review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1979. (Box 55)
    Non Lieu. Paris.
    Fondane, Benjamin.
  - NOTRE PAIX [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1943. (Box 55)
    ER's note: BOOKS ABROAD, 1943.
  - OVERCOMING ANTISEMITISM by Solomon Andhil Fineberg [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 55)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: TOMORROW MAGAZINE.
  - Paris galleries and museums review by Roditi, Edouard., 1983 March. (Box 55)
    L'Arche. Paris.
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: L'ARCHE, Paris, March 1983. Beginning, "La tres belle exposition, au Grand Palais, des peintres de 'L'Ecole de La Haye: Les maitres hollandais du dix-neuvieme siecle' ..."
  - Paris galleries and museums review by Roditi, Edouard., 1983. (Box 55)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: L'ARCHE, Paris, 1983. Beginning, "Il y a quelques mois, L'ARCHE annoncait brievement que les Salons de la Rose Croix A.M.O.R.C. ... "
  - Paris galleries and museums review by Roditi, Edouard., 1984 Nov. (Box 55)
    ER's note: L'ARCHE, Nov. 1984. Beginning, "Depuis de nombreuses annees, nous faisons regulierement l'eloge, dans ces chroniques ... Paul Eliasberg ..."
  - Paris galleries and museums review by Roditi, Edouard., 1984 Nov. (Box 55)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: L'ARCHE, Nov. 1984. Beginning, "Avec le FIAC (Foire Internationale de l'Art Contemporain) au Grand Palais ... "
  - PIERO DI COSIMO by R. Langton Douglas [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 55)
  - Poems, 1928-1948 - Preface by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 55)
    ER's note: first draft a preface, not published.
  - POESIE ALLEMANDE D'AUJOURD HUI by Pierre Garnier [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 55)
  - Poetry as propaganda [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 55)
    ER's note: POETRY. Review of ODE TO BOMBED LONDON by Philippe Soupault, THREE PRAYERS FOR PILOTS by Jules Roy.
  - Present indicative by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 55)
  - QUESTOES DE GRAMATICA LATINA by Raul Machado, 2 vols. [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1941?. (Box 55)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: CLASSICAL PHILOLOGY, 1941? VOLUME I: PROUNUNCIA DO LATIN E ELEMENTOS DE FONETICA HISTORICA LATINA, VOLUME II: MORFOLOGIA GENERAL E ELEMENTOS DE MORFOLOGIA HISTORICA.
  - Recent poetry of Ivan Goll by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 55)
    ER's note: DIOGENES.
  - REPARTO DE TIERRAS by Cesar M. Arconada [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 55)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: PREUVES, LETTRES ETRANGERES SUPPLEMENT.
  - Studies of the Sephardic Diaspora [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1982. (Box 55)
    ER's note: PRESENT TENSE, New York, 1984. Review of LA AMERICA ... by Marc D. Angel; MOSAIQUES DE NOTRE TEMPS ... by Sarah Leibovici.
    Angel, Marc D. La America: The sephardic experience in the United States.
    Leibovici, Sarah, ed. Mosaiques de notre temps: Les juifs espagnole du Maroc.
  - Suggested criteria of human values [book review and essay] by Roditi, Edouard., 1978. (Box 55)
    ER's note: VIRGINIA WOOLF QUARTERLY, 1978. Review of REVOLUTION OF THE WORD: A NEW GATHERING OF AMERICAN AVANT-GARDE POETRY, 1914-1945 by Jerome Rothenberg,
  - SULLA LIRICA ROMANZA DELLE ORIGINI by Guido Errante [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1943 - 1944?. (Box 55)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: BOOKS ABROAD, 1943-1944?
  - Tamara de Lempicka by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 55)
    ER's note: Unpublished.
  - UN ETRANGE VOYAGE by Nazim Hikmet [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1981. (Box 55)
  - WOUNDED ALPHABET by George Hitchcock [book review] by Roditi, Edouard., 1984. (Box 55)
    Untitled manuscript. Full title: THE WOUNDED ALPHABET. ER'S note: EXQUISITE CORPSE, 1984.
  - Self-portrait by Voronca, Ilarie., 1988. (Box 55)
    English translation by ER. With 2 pages of biographical notes on Jewish poets living in France. With ER's note, "SHIRIM, Los Angeles".
    Vigee, Claude.
    Jabes, Edmond.
  - A travers les galeries parisiennes by Roditi, Edouard., 1971. (Box 56)
    ER's note: JEUNE AFRIQUE, 1971.
  - Adler by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
    Re artist Yankel Adler.
  - Ahmed Cherkaoui: peinture et parousie by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
    ER's note: JEUNE AFRIQUE. With 3 photos of Cherkaoui paintings.
  - Alexej von Jawlensky by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
    German translation by Alexander Koval.
  - Alexis de Jawlensky ou l'evolution d'un peintre mystique de l'eglise orthodoxe by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 56)
  - Arslan by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
    Re artist Yueksel Arslan.
  - Braque and the tests of time by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 56)
    ER's note: NEW LEADER. Two pages are numbered 4.
    Braque, Georges
  - Brauner by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
    Re Erich Brauner.
  - Buffet by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
    Buffet, Bernard
  - Carlo Carra by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
  - Cesar by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
  - Chez nos voisins du nord by Roditi, Edouard., 1969 Dec. (Box 56)
    ER's note: L'ARCHE, December 1969.
  - Chronique artistique by Roditi, Edouard., 1963. (Box 56)
    ER's note: ARCADIE.
  - Chronique Sefardite by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
  - Elegie pour une ville morte by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
  - Entretien avec Emmanuel Pereire by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
  - Ettore Sottsass on industrial design by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 56)
  - Friedrich Schroeder Sonnenstern by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
    ER's note: PRISME.
  - Fureyya Koral by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
  - Georg Grosz: An embittered romantic by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
  - Grandeur ou servitude d'un art dissident by Roditi, Edouard., 1981 June. (Box 56)
    ER's note: L'ARCHE, June 1981.
  - Grosz by Roditi, Edouard., n.d.; [2 folders] (Box 56)
    Grosz, George
  - Harloff by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
  - Ida Kerkovius by Roditi, Edouard., n.d.; [2 folders] (Box 56)
    German and French versions.
  - In erdnaehe - down to earth - scrutez la terre by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
    Re: Heinz Troekes.
  - Joachim Karsch (1897-1945) by Roditi, Edouard., n.d.; [2 folders] (Box 56)
  - Juifs de partout et de toutes les couleurs by Roditi, Edouard., 1975. (Box 56)
    ER's note: L'ARCHE, Summer 1975.
  - Jussuf Abbo by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
  - La belle epoque by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
    Re Demetrios Galanis.
  - Legendes et realites de juif errant by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 56)
  - Manuel Cargaleiro, peintre portugais de l'Ecole de Paris by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
  - Marcelle Cahn by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
  - Meidner by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
    Signed on page 4 by ER.
    Meidner, Ludwig
  - Memoirs and legends [book review] by Roditi, Edouard. (Box 56)
    Review of LA RUCHE by Jacques Chapiro, and 14 CITE FALGUIERRE by Diogo de Macedo.
  - Michaux by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
    Michaux, Henri
  - Neglected Fauvist master: Bela Czobel by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
  - Niki de Saint-Phalle by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
  - On the interpretation of emblems by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
    Re: Harloff.
  - Ossip Zadkin [Zadkine] by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
  - Paris galleries and museums review by Roditi, Edouard., 1985 Fall. (Box 56)
    Untitled manuscript. ER's note: PASSION, Fall 1985.
  - Paris interview with Leonor Fini by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
  - Peintres et galeries de Tanger by Roditi, Edouard., n.d. (Box 56)
    ER's note: JEUNE AFRIQUE.